Meet Phillip and Marlowe, the post-nuclear private eyes. They're looking for good
times and fast women. Their first case could be the world's last.
Radioactive Dreams is a science fiction, action,
adventure film directed by Albert Pyun.
After an atomic war Phillip Hammer and Marlowe Chandler have spent 15 years on their own
in an bunker, stuffed with junk from the 40s and old detective novels.
Now, 19 years old, they leave their shelter to find a
world full of mutants, freaks and cannibals.
They become famous detectives in the struggle for the two
keys that could fire the last nuclear weapon.
Phillip Chandler, played by John Stockwell.
Marlowe Hammer, played by Michael Dudikoff.
Miles Archer, played by Lisa Blount.
Spade Chandler, played by George Kennedy.
Dash Hammer, played by Don Murray.
Rusty Mars, played by Michele Little.
Radioactive Dreams is a 1984 post-apocalyptic science fiction-comedy film written and directed by
Albert Pyun and starring George Kennedy, Michael Dudikoff, Don Murray, and Lisa Blount.
The names of the two main characters are homages to noir detective fiction
icons Philip Marlowe, Raymond Chandler and Mike Hammer.
The film has achieved cult status and has been screened in
several cult revival programs around the world.
The film begins with two boys growing up in a fallout
shelter, in an attempt to escape a nuclear war.
They rejoin the world in 2001, and soon acquire the
activation keys of the world's last nuclear missile.
They get involved in gang warfare in their new environment.
The film explores themes of detective, mutant, post-apocalyptic future.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.